export const chapter =
  "Chapter - 20: Agricultural Development and Case Studies ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary reason for the need to undertake steps for agricultural development?",
        optionA: "Increase in industrial production",
        optionB: "Growing population",
        optionC: "Expansion of transportation networks",
        correctAnswer: "B) Growing population",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which factor is contributing to the shrinking of agricultural land?",
        optionA: "Modern way of living",
        optionB: "Increased use of chemical fertilizers",
        optionC: "Expansion of employment schemes",
        correctAnswer: "C) Expansion of employment schemes",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is a negative consequence of the shift from home-cooked food to packaged food and catering services?",
        optionA: "Reduced food variety",
        optionB: "Increased food wastage",
        optionC: "Higher food prices",
        correctAnswer: "B) Increased food wastage",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is a significant negative impact of the large-scale use of chemical fertilizers and pesticides on agriculture?",
        optionA: "Improved soil fertility",
        optionB: "Increased crop yields",
        optionC: "Soil fertility loss",
        correctAnswer: "C) Soil fertility loss",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During which period did the Industrial Revolution lead to a remarkable change in the agricultural scenario worldwide?",
        optionA: "17th century",
        optionB: "19th century",
        optionC: "21st century",
        correctAnswer: "B) 19th century",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the percentage contribution of agriculture to India's GDP (gross domestic product)?",
        optionA: "10%",
        optionB: "18%",
        optionC: "27.4%",
        correctAnswer: "C) 27.4%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What significant changes were introduced to Indian agriculture after gaining independence in 1947?",
        optionA: "Traditional farming methods were maintained",
        optionB: "Land reforms and modern farming methods were introduced",
        optionC: "The focus shifted to industrial development",
        correctAnswer:
          "B) Land reforms and modern farming methods were introduced",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the term used to describe the significant increase in food production in India after the government's initiatives?",
        optionA: "Industrial Revolution",
        optionB: "Blue Revolution",
        optionC: "Green Revolution",
        correctAnswer: "C) Green Revolution",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the main issue leading to farmers' suicides in India?",
        optionA: "Excessive debt",
        optionB: "Lack of government support",
        optionC: "Unfavorable weather conditions",
        correctAnswer: "A) Excessive debt",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What negative impact is associated with the excessive use of chemical fertilizers, pesticides, and machines in Indian agriculture?",
        optionA: "Increased crop yields",
        optionB: "Water and environmental pollution",
        optionC: "Enhanced soil fertility",
        correctAnswer: "B) Water and environmental pollution",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Agriculture is directly related to food security. We depend on agriculture not only for our nutritional needs but also for raw materials required by many industries. This is the reason that there is a need to undertake steps for agricultural _________.",
        optionA: "progress",
        optionB: "modernization",
        optionC: "development",
        correctAnswer: "C) development",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The population is growing rapidly, with the world population increasing at about 1.1% per year, resulting in approximately 8.2 crore people being added to it each year. In India, the population was approximately 136 crore in 2019, up from 121 crore in 2011. This growing population requires agricultural ________ and ________.",
        optionA: "expansion; innovation",
        optionB: "sustainability; modernization",
        optionC: "expansion; development",
        correctAnswer: "C) expansion; development",
      },
      {
        question:
          "With the growing population, more land is needed for activities other than agriculture, such as settlement, construction of roads and railways, and employment schemes. In other words, agricultural land is _________.",
        optionA: "expanding",
        optionB: "shrinking",
        optionC: "stabilizing",
        correctAnswer: "B) shrinking",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Modern ways of living have expanded food needs; at present, a person consumes more varied food than in the past. People are gradually shifting from home-cooked food to catering services and packaged food, which results in a large-scale _________ of food.",
        optionA: "conservation",
        optionB: "production",
        optionC: "wastage",
        correctAnswer: "C) wastage",
      },
      {
        question:
          "As more crops are grown on a commercial basis, the soil is losing its fertility owing to the large-scale use of _________ and _________.",
        optionA: "organic fertilizers; natural pesticides",
        optionB: "chemical fertilizers; pesticides",
        optionC: "natural fertilizers; synthetic pesticides",
        correctAnswer: "B) chemical fertilizers; pesticides",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution in the 18th and early 19th centuries led to remarkable changes in the agricultural scenario worldwide. Improved methods of farming, advances in livestock breeding, and the invention of farm equipment brought about a steady growth in the agriculture sector. The use of high-yielding varieties of seeds, application of fertilizers, pesticides, and insecticides aided in this achievement. Much of the farm work in developed countries is _________.",
        optionA: "manual labor-intensive",
        optionB: "biologically driven",
        optionC: "mechanized",
        correctAnswer: "C) mechanized",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India's agriculture continues to be the backbone of its economy, contributing about 27.4% of the GDP (gross domestic product), while its share in exports is about 18%. In 1947, when India gained freedom, the condition of agriculture was pathetic, leading to food shortages and famines. The government took several measures to develop agriculture, including the introduction of land reforms, irrigation, electricity, transportation, and the provision of farming equipment, such as tractors, threshers, harvesters, high-yielding varieties of seeds, and _________.",
        optionA: "natural fertilizers",
        optionB: "synthetic pesticides",
        optionC: "fertilizers",
        correctAnswer: "C) fertilizers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "All these measures helped India become self-reliant in agricultural production. At present, India is a major producer of cereals, oilseeds, vegetables, fruits, and is the largest producer of _________ in the world.",
        optionA: "cotton",
        optionB: "rubber",
        optionC: "milk",
        correctAnswer: "C) milk",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Despite such good development, there is a negative impact too. Many farmers take extreme steps when they fall into a debt trap or when natural calamities, like flood or drought, destroy their crops. The excessive use of chemical fertilizers, pesticides, and machines has a negative effect on the land's fertility, which means that more chemical fertilizers and pesticides will have to be used in the coming times, simply aggravating the present _________.",
        optionA: "challenges",
        optionB: "issues",
        optionC: "problems",
        correctAnswer: "C) problems",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In view of the above discussion, it is important that the government takes steps to address the problems associated with agriculture. The government is already taking steps for farmers' welfare, but these welfare measures need to be delivered to the poorest farmers. The farmers should be trained in modern farming techniques and proper use of machinery, and they should be made aware of the negative effects of their farming practices, like water and environmental _________.",
        optionA: "conservation",
        optionB: "sustainability",
        optionC: "pollution",
        correctAnswer: "C) pollution",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Agriculture is directly related to food security.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question: "The world population is growing at about 1.1% per year.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "With the growing population, agricultural land is expanding.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Modern ways of living have led to a reduction in food wastage.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The use of chemical fertilizers and pesticides has a positive impact on soil fertility.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Industrial Revolution in the 18th and early 19th centuries had no significant impact on agriculture.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question: "India is traditionally an industrial country.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government introduced land reforms to redistribute land among landless laborers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Indian farmers primarily use organic fertilizers in their farming practices.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has not taken any steps to address the problems associated with agriculture.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
